Ruth Frances Woodsmall Papers, 1863-1968
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES
  - United Nations
    - UNICEF: "Digest of UNICEF Aided Projects," 1958 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - UNESCO, 1955-56, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - United States Mission to the UN, 1949, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958-60 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - U.N. Story (four 10 inch phonograph recordings), undated (Box 51)
  - U.S. High Commissioner for Germany
    - Conferences (Box 51)
      - Bad Reichenhall International Women's Conference Sept, 1950 (Box 51)
        - Correspondence, 1950-52, n.d (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Delegates and participants, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Organizational materials and budgets, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Programs, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - Publicity, 1950-51, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
        - Reports, 1950, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Chiemsee International Conference on Comparative Education,1949 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - German Women's Exchange Conference, 1952, [see also Projects and Programs - Exchange programs] (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Hindelang Conference, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Informal Women's Conference, 1949 (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - International Conference of Young Women (September 1951), 1951 (Box 52)
        - Addresses (Box 52, Folder 11)
        - Agenda, programs, participants, and reports (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Correspondence (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Printed material (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - International Women's Conference, Chiemsee, 1949-50 (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - Koferenz der Arbeitsgemeinschaft der Wahlerinnen, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Panel of Eleven Prominent American Women (American Voluntary Agencies) (Apr - Jun 1951), 1950-51 (Box 52)
        - Agenda, programs and schedules (Box 53, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence (Box 53, Folder 2)
        - Participants (Box 53, Folder 3)
        - Publicity (Box 53, Folder 4)
        - Reports (Box 53, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Resident Officers Conferences, 1950, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Seminar on Civic Education (Koenigstein), 1950 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Vocational Guidance Conference (Koenigstein), 1952 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Wives of American Officials in Germany and Women Representatives of HICOG, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - World Council of Churches Tour, 1949-50 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Zonal Conference on American Women's Activities, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-52, undated (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1948-52, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Organization and administration (Box 54)
      - Budgets, 1950-51 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Educational and Cultural Division, 1949-50 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - History and organizational materials, 1947-52, undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda, 1949-51 (Box 5)
      - Personnel, 1948-52, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Publications (Box 5)
        - Occupied Countries News Notes, 1949-52 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Woodsmall, Ruth (Box 5)
      - Appointment and financial materials, 1949-52, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Identification papers, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Memorabilia, 1938-51, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Notes, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Speeches and reports, 1945-49 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Projects and programs (Box 5)
      - Citizen Training Project (Box 5)
        - Budgets, 1950-52, [see also Tripartite Projects] (Box 55, Folder 1)
        - Descriptions, 1950-53, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
        - Lectures, 1951, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
        - Reports, 1950-52, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous, 1950-51, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Exchange programs (Box 55)
        - Exchange Conference of German Women Who Have Participated in Exchange Programs, 1951-52, undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
        - Reports and evaluations (Box 55)
          - B-M, 1959, undated (Box 55, Folder 7)
          - O-W and miscellaneous, 1949-50, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
          - Staff, 1949-52 (Box 55)
        - Statistics, 1947-49, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous, 1947-53 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - German Women's Organizations, 1951-52, [see also Subjects-German Women's Organizations] (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Preparing Women as Effective Citizens in Economic Life, 1951 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - Reference Bureau for German Women's Organizations, 1951-52, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Reorientation Project, 1949-50 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Tripartite Projects, 1951 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - U.S. Information and Educational Exchange, 1951 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Women's Advisory Committee in Bavaria, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Women's Affairs, Hesse, 1950-51 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Women's Institute for Training of Leadership in Citizen Education, 1950, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1948-51, undated (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Publicity (Box 56)
      - Press releases, 1949-52 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Public Information Office, 1949-52, undated (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Public Relations Division, 1949-51 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Radio Frankfurt (Box 56)
        - Gabrielle Strecker broadcast (Box 56)
          - Correspondence to Gabrielle Strecker, 1951-52, undated (Box 56, Folder 12)
          - Miscellaneous, 1951-53 (Box 56, Folder 13)
        - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Reports (Box 56)
      - Administrative (Box 56)
        - Daily, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 1)
        - Monthly, 1949-51 (Box 57, Folder 2)
        - Semi-annual, 1949-51 (Box 57, Folder 3)
        - Highlights, 1951-52 (Box 57, Folder 4)
        - Women's Affairs, 1948-51 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - American Women's Organization Panel, [see Conferences] (Box 57)
      - Consultants and specialists (Box 57)
        - A-C, 1952-59 (Box 57, Folder 6)
        - Eckel, Rhea, 1948-49 (Box 57, Folder 7)
        - Fackt, Elizabeth, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 8)
        - F-W, 1948-52 (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - East Zone, 1949, undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - German women's activities, 1948-49, undated, [see also Subjects - German Women's Organizations] (Box 57, Folder 11)
      - Visits to Germany, 1948-49 (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - Visits to United States, 1949-52, undated (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - Vocational Guidance and Occupational Activities of Women in Germany, 1952 (Box 57, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1949-53, undated (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Subjects (Box 57)
      - Berlin Blockade, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - British Zone, 1947-49 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund, 1948-49, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - Civil rights, 1949-51, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - Communism and socialism, 1949-53, undated (Box 58, Folder 5-9)
      - Cultural affairs, 1949-53 (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - Economic recovery, 1947-50 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - Education, 1948-51, undated (Box 58, Folder 12)
      - Elections, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Employment and labor, 1949-52, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Farm women, 1947-50, undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - German occupation, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - German Society for Foreign Study, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - German unification, 1949-52, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - German women (Box 59)
        - Lists, 1948-52, undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
        - Status, 1947-52, undated (Box 59, Folder 8)
        - Organizations, 1949-52, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - Germany and German history, 1948-54 (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - Housing, 1950 (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Informationen Fuer Die Frau, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Nationalism, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - Nazism, 1933-52 (Box 59, Folder 14)
      - Refugees, 1950, undated (Box 59, Folder 15)
      - Religion and religious affairs, 1949-52, undated (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
      - Statistics, 1946-49 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Women's health, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Women's International Democratic Federation (WIDF), [see Communism and socialism] (Box 60)
      - Women's Manifesto, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - World YWCA/YMCA, 1947-51 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-53, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - YWCA
    - 1914-1918 (World War I) (Box 60)
      - Hostess Houses (Box 60)
        - Camp Pike, Arkansas, 1917-18 (Box 61, Folder 1)
        - Clippings, 1917-18 (Box 61, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence from guests, 1918 (Box 61, Folder 3)
        - Reports and miscellaneous materials, 1917-18 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - American YWCA in France, 1917-18 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Reports on war work, 1914-18 (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - War Work Bulletin, 1917-19 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Women's War Work, 1918 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Post World War I (Box 61)
      - England (reports from RW on her way to France), 1918 (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - France (Box 62)
        - News releases, 1918, undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
        - Reports (Box 62)
          - Summer camps, 1919, undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
          - War brides, 1919-20, undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
          - Miscellaneous, 1919, undated (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Germany, 1919, n.d (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - Switzerland (Box 62)
        - Champery Conference, 1920 (Box 62, Folder 7)
        - International Suffrage Conference (Geneva), 1920 (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - Emigration investigation, 1920, undated (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Field surveys (Box 62)
        - Balkans and Baltic states, 1919, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
        - Near East (Box 63)
          - Conferences (Box 63)
            - Beirut, 1928 (Box 63, Folder 2)
            - Jerusalem, 1928 (Box 63, Folder 3)
          - Constantinople, 1920 (Box 63, Folder 4)
          - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 63, Folder 5)
          - Lausanne Treaty, 1926-27, undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
            - Reports (Box 63)
              - Interim, 1921-28, undated (Box 63, Folder 7-11)
              - Final: "Near East Survey," 1928 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Conferences (Box 63)
      - International Suffrage Alliance, Istanbul, 1935 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - National Industrial Assembly, Columbus, OH, 1937-38 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Social Service Conference, 1931 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - World Conference of Christian Youth, 1947, undated (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - World Council of the YMCA, 1957 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - World Council (Box 64)
        - Ontario, Canada, 1936-40 (Box 64, Folder 6)
        - Washington, D.C. 1941 (Box 64, Folder 7)
        - Hangchow, China, 1947 (Box 64, Folder 8)
        - Beirut, Lebanon, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 9)
        - Cuernavaca, Mexico, 1959 (Box 64, Folder 10)
        - World Council Reference Book, 1930-47 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - Young Leaders Conference, 1946 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1935-53, undated (Box 65, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence (Box 65)
      - General (Box 65)
        - 1928-43, undated (Box 66, Folder 1-12)
        - 1934-62, undated (Box 67, Folder 1-5)
      - Cushman, Vera, 1932-44, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Heim, Virginia, 1942 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Lyon, Sarah S., 1926-42, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Mills, Marianne, 1938-63, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Palmer, Elizabeth, 1948-60 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Rouse, Ruth, 1937-54 (Box 68, Folder 6-9)
      - Van Asch van Wijck, Cornelia, 1934-62, undated (Box 68, Folder 10-13)
    - Organization and administration (Box 68)
      - Anniversaries, 1932-43 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Budgets and financial material, 1932-48, undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Executive Committee (Box 69)
        - Correspondence, reports, and miscellaneous material, 1932-55 (Box 69, Folder 3-4)
        - Ruth Woodsmall reports to Executive Committee and World Council, 1929-52, undated (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
      - History and constitution, undated (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Memorabilia, 1936-47, undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Policies, 1936-49, undated (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Public relations, 1946 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Reports (Box 70)
        - Annual Reports of the General Secretary, 1938-46, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous, 1934-47, undated (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Staff, 1934-46, undated (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Woodsmall, Ruth (Box 70)
      - Employment materials, 1932-46 (Box 70, Folder 8)
      - Interviews, 1934-44, undated (Box 70, Folder 9)
      - Letters of congratulation on appointment as General Secretary, 1935-36, undated (Box 70, Folder 10)
      - Notes, undated (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Reports, 1934-46, undated (Box 70, Folder 12)
      - Schedules and itineraries, 1934-47, undated (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Speeches, 1935-45 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Publications (Box 70)
      - Blue Triangle, 1940-52 (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Foreign Mail, 1931-33 (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - World YWCA Monthly, 1935-47 (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1934-58 (Box 71, Folder 4-5)
    - Subjects (Box 71)
      - Adult education, 1934-37 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - American Interorganization in Geneva, 1939 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - Communism and socialism, 1935-47 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Countries and regions (Box 72)
        - Africa, 1956, undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
        - Australia and New Zealand, 1938-47, undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
        - Canada, 1937-42, undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
        - China, 1930-48, undated (Box 72, Folder 7-10)
        - Europe (Box 72)
          - Eastern, 1931-73, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
          - Northern, 1939-47 (Box 72, Folder 12)
          - Southern, 1939-47, undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
          - Miscellaneous, 1935-43 (Box 73, Folder 2)
        - Far East, 1933-47 (Box 73, Folder 3)
        - France, 1938-45, undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
        - Germany, 1934-52, undated (Box 73, Folder 5)
        - Great Britain, 1932-47 (Box 73, Folder 6)
        - India, Burma, and Ceylon, 1934-61, undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
        - Japan, 1931-50, undated (Box 73, Folder 8)
        - Korea, 1930-32, undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
        - Latin America (Box 74)
          - Notes on Latin American trip, 1942-43 (Box 74, Folder 2)
          - Report of five months in Latin America, 1942 (Box 74, Folder 3)
          - Miscellaneous, 1931-46, undated (Box 74, Folder 4)
        - Middle East and North Africa, 1931-49, undated (Box 74, Folder 5)
        - Pacific Islands, 1937-50, undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
        - Philippines, 1932-59, undated (Box 74, Folder 7)
        - West Indies, 1943 (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Disarmament, 1930 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Economic development, 1940-42, undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - Emergency Commission of Christian Organizations, 1939-40 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Federation des Institutions Internationales, 1939 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Geneva Research Center, 1943-48 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Girls work, 1939 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Hostels, 1944-46 (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - International Study Group, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - League of Nations, 1919-46 (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Rationing, 1943 (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Reconstruction, 1941-45 (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Refugees, Internees, and POWs (Box 75)
        - Austria, 1945-52, undated (Box 75, Folder 12)
        - France, 1939-45, undated (Box 75, Folder 13)
        - Germany, 1939-51, undated (Box 75, Folder 14)
        - Hungary and Romania, 1939-40, undated (Box 75, Folder 15)
        - Norway, 1940-43, undated (Box 75, Folder 16)
        - Miscellaneous, 1939-53, undated (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Religion, 1938-62, undated (Box 76, Folder 1-2)
      - Rural life, 1932-46 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - War work (World War II), 1920-46, undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - Women and the church, 1937-61, undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - Women and society, 1936-48, undated (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - Women's groups, 1951 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - World Christian Community, undated (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - World Council of Churches, 1939-46 (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - World Emergency Fund, undated (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - World Fellowship, 1941-42 (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - World Student Christian Federation, 1939-42 (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - YMCA/YWCA, 1936-48, undated (Box 76, Folder 14)
      - Youth work, 1939-46, undated (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous organizations and itineraries, 1948-63 (Box 76, Folder 16)
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES
  - Church and Christian organizations, 1939-40, undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Ewha University, 1961-63, undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Federal Union, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Gandhigram, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Islam, 1961 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - League of Nations, 1936-37 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Hiroshima Peace Center Association, 1952 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Speeches (miscellaneous), 1938, 1953, undated (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Status of Women, 1942-59, undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
- SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Ruth Woodsmall
    - Alone (Box 77)
      - pre 1916 (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - circa 1915-48 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - circa 1949- (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - YWCA publicity photographs, undated (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Groups (Box 78)
      - Australia, 1939 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - HICOG, 1952, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
        - Identified, 1901-57, undated (Box 78, Folder 7-8)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Family
    - Eldredge, Helen Woodsmall, 1935, undated (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Neumann (Box 79)
      - Marlen Eldredge, 1930, 1942, n.d (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Children, 1945-51, undated (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Robert, undated (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous family and friends, undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Woodsmall (Box 79)
      - Hubert H., 1937-45, undated, [See also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Mary Elizabeth (Howes), undated (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1876-1961, undated (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Friends and associates
    - A-Z, 1924-67, n.d (Box 80, Folder 1-3)
    - Unidentified, 1924-56, undated (Box 80, Folder 4-6)
  - Public figures
    - Menon, Lakshmi, undated (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1951, undated (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Pandit, Vijayalakshmi, 1952, undated (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, undated (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Professional activities
    - YWCA (Box 80)
      - Beirut, 1933, undated (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - China, undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Classes, undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - Conferences, 1925-48, undated (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Greece, undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - Israel and Palestine, 1929-43, undated (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Japan, 1932, 1955, undated (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - Syria and Jordan, 1930-33, undated (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - Turkey, [see also Subjects - Countries] (Box 81)
        - Constantinople, 1922-26, undated (Box 81, Folder 9-10)
        - Smyrna, 1921, undated (Box 81, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous, 1925, undated (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - World War I: War work and hostess clubs, 1920s, [see also - Subjects] (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - World War II, [see also - Subjects] (Box 82)
      - Hostess clubs and mobile club vans, 1940s (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Refugee work, 1940s (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939, 1951, undated (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - U.S. High Commissioner for Germany (Box 82)
    - Conferences (Box 82)
      - American Women's Organizations, 1951 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Five Day Conference, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - Kreis Resident Conference, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Women in public life, 1951 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1948, undated (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - United Nations (Box 83)
    - Egypt, 1954, undated (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - India, 1954, undated (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Iran and Iraq, 1954-56, undated (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Pakistan, 1954, undated (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-54, undated (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Subjects
    - Conferences, 1931-57, undated (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Countries (Box 84)
      - Arabia, 1929, undated (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - Burma, undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
      - China (Box 84)
        - Chapei, undated (Box 84, Folder 4)
        - Refugee children, undated (Box 84, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Egypt, 1931, undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Germany, undated (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - India, 1929-59, undated (Box 85, Folder 3-6)
      - Indonesia, 1952, undated (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Iran, 1935-56, undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - Iraq, undated (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - Japan, 1930-32, undated (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Korea, 1932, undated (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - Lebanon, undated (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - Pakistan, 1930-57, undated (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Philippines, 1936, undated (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Poland, 1918-20, undated (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Russia, undated (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Switzerland (Geneva), undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
      - Syria, undated (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Thailand, undated (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Turkey (Box 87)
        - Smyrna, undated (Box 87, Folder 8)
        - "Where East and West Meet: Constantinople" (album), undated (Box 87, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous, 1931, undated (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - World War I, [see also YWCA] (Box 87)
      - England (occupations), [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS - glass slides] (Box 87)
        - Farm workers (Land Girls), undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
        - Munitions and airplane manufacturing, undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
        - Photocopies of glass slides located in Box 89 (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - France, undated (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - World War II, [see also YWCA] (Box 88)
      - WAACs and WRENs, undated (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - War scenes, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
      - War work, 1942, undated (Box 88, Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Wooden box containing 24 glass slide negatives of women and World War I (Box 89)
  - Photo album: 11 member panel of women visiting Germany to work with German women leaders and their organizations under the auspices of the Women's Affairs Branch, HICOG April 1951 (Box 90)
  - "A Book of Famous and Beautiful Chinese Women from Antiquity," undated (Box 90)
  - Academic hood (Indiana University) (Box 91)
  - Photographs (Box 92)
    - Hubert H. Woodsmall (Ruth Woodsmall's brother) undated (Box 92)
    - Women's Affairs VIP (HICOG) 1950 (Box 92)
    - "How Good to Find a Home" (HICOG) (Box 92)
    - "What tonight?"(HICOG) (Box 92)
    - UNESCO Human Rights Day 1951 (Box 92)
    - U.S. Information Service, Lahore: women learning to operate movie projectors (Box 92)
  - Menu/cartoon: World Population Conference, Geneva 1927 (Box 92)
  - Moslem calendar (Box 92)
  - Jupiter Rex (Pan American - Grace Airways) certificate undated (Box 92)
  - Women's Affair Yearly Reports 1948-51 (Box 92)
  - Layman's Foreign Missions Inquiry Appraisal Commission reports 1932 (Box 92)
  - Passport 1917 (Box 92)
  - Honorary degree certificate, Indiana University 1956 (Box 92)
  - Chinese map undated (Box 92)
  - YWCA Chinese certificate undated (Box 92)
  - Chanson ce L'Escalade 1602: poster undated (Box 92)
  - 2 Chinese drawings (Box 92)
  - Oil painting: Autumn Moon Pavillion, Hanchow, China undated (Box 92)
  - Colored print: nativity scene undated (Box 92)
  - Chinese character block prints undated (Box 92)